Guide to the Religious Life Reference collection, 1937-ongoing UA.01.11.0035
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Religious Life Reference collection
1937-ongoing
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. University Archives
UA.01.11.0035
0.8 Linear Feet
The Religious Life Reference Collection contains files of clippings, brochures, handbooks, memoranda and other material concerning the religious life of the University community.
800 Items
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
This collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
Biographical/Historical note
Chronology
1936 - Office of Religious Activities established
1938 - Duke University Church (non-denominational) founded; disbanded 1985
1956 - Duke University Religious Council founded
1985 - Congregation at Duke University founded
Scope and Contents note
The Religious Life Reference Collection contains files of clippings, brochures, memoranda and other material concerning the religious life of the University community. The bulk of the material concerns student religious life. The handbook, Religious Life, Duke University, 1954-1965 (incomplete run) includes descriptions of student religious organizations, events and programs. Materials in the collection pertain to both local and national religious organizations active at the University. Among the national organizations represented are The Campus Crusade for Christ; United Campus Christian Fellowship, and United Student Fellowship. Local groups represented include campus chapters of denominational organizations, and the Coalition on Chapel Policy, a committee formed in 1979/80 to advocate for changes in the Chapel’s administrative procedures after University Minister Robert Young dismissed Assistant Minister Helen Crotwell.
Related Material
Duke University Chapel Reference Collection, 1932-
Duke University Archives
Duke University Church Records, 1937-1985
Duke University Archives
Hindu Student Association Records
Duke University Archives
Lutheran Student Ministry, [1949-1974]
Duke University Archives
Religious Council Records, 1937-1971
Duke University Archives
Student Organizations Reference Collection
Duke University Archives
United Methodist -Presbyterian Ministry, [1949-1974]
Duke University Archives
Young Men’s Christian Association, Duke University Chapter Records, 1920-1969
Duke University Archives
Young Women’s Christian Association Duke University Chapter Records, 1930-1970
Duke University Archives
Young Men's--Young Women's Christian Association Records, 1968-1979
Duke University Archives
College students -- Durham, NC -- Religious life; Crotwell, Helen, Rev; Duke University Church; Duke University -- Religion; Duke University. Office of Religious Activities; Duke University. University Archives; Duke University. Minister to the University; Duke University. Religious Life Council; Young, Robert, Rev
- Religious life administration, 1937-1982, undated
  Scope and Contents note
  Arrangement: alphabetical by folder title
  Contents: Reports, handbooks, clippings, flyers, and other materials concerning the administration of religious life activities. Subjects include programming, services, and staffing matters.
  - Administration (Box 1)
  - Duke University Campus Ministry, 1981- (Box 1)
  - Duke University Campus Ministry Meditations for Lent, 1981, 1983, 1984 and Meditations for Advent, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Duke University Church (Box 1)
  - Duke University Parish Ministry, 1971-1981 (Box 1)
  - Minister to the University Reports, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Religious Activities Reports, 1940, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Religious Emphasis Week, 1943-1957 (inc.) (Box 1)
  - Religious Life: Duke University [handbook], 1954-1965 (Box 1)
  - Religious life advisory group, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Religious life flyers (Box 1)
  - Religious life clippings (Box 1)
  - Duplicates (Box 1)
- Religious organizations, 1953-2000, undated
  Contents: Newsletters, flyers, reports, clippings, and other materials produced by or about local and national religious organizations active on campus.
  - Baha'i Club, 1971-1981 (Box 2)
  - Baptist Student Union, 1976-1990 (Box 2)
  - Baptist Student Union (at Duke), BSU Broadcaster, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Baptist Student Union (at Duke), The Prophet, 1953 (Box 2)
  - Baptist Student Union of North Carolina, The Reveille, 1954-1957 (Box 2)
  - Campus Crusade for Christ, 1971-1984 (Box 2)
  - Christian Science Organization at Duke University, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Christian Social Action Committee, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Duke Christian Fellowship (Box 2)
  - Episcopal Student Center, 1959-1987 (Box 2)
  - Fellowship of Christian Athletes (Box 2)
  - Hillel Foundation/Society, circa 1953-1996 (Box 2)
  - Inter-varsity Christian Fellowship, 1968-1981 (Box 2)
  - Islamic Association at Duke, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Muslim Student Association, 1979, 2000, undated (Box 2)
  - Navigators, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Newman Catholic Student Center, 1984-2000 (Box 2)
  - Political Action in Christ (PAX), 1977 (Box 2)
  - Presbyterian Student Association, 1985-1989, undated (Box 2)
  - Raptures: A Christian Fellowship, undated (Box 2)
  - Unitarian Fellowship, 1955-1956 (Box 2)
  - Unitarian Fellowship, Duke-Durham, The Duke Beacon, 1956 (Box 2)
  - United Campus Christian Fellowship, 1968 (Box 2)
  - United Student Christian Coalition Comminique, 1951-1957 (Box 2)
  - United Student Fellowship Encounter, 1956-1957 (Box 2)
  - United Student Fellowship Resource, 1954-1957 (Box 2)
  - University Christian Movement, 1966-1968 (Box 2)
  - Wesley Fellowship Reports, 1989-1996 (Box 2)
  - Wesley Fellowship Newsletters and Flyers, circa 1984 (Box 2)